import { Topic } from '.'

export const set9: Topic = {
  topic: 'RMS Class 6 General Knowledge',
  level: 'Intermediate',
  totalQuestions: 50,
  totalScore: 500,
  totalTime: 3000,
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'Periyar National Park is located in which state?',
      choices: ['Andhra Pradesh', 'Kerala', 'Karnataka', 'Tamil Nadu'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Kerala'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Where are Ajanta and Ellora Caves located?',
      choices: ['Odisha', 'Telangana', 'Maharashtra', 'Karnataka'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Maharashtra'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'When is Hindi Day observed?',
      choices: ['September 10', 'September 12', 'September 14', 'September 15'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['September 14'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which is the National Game of India?',
      choices: ['Hockey', 'Football', 'Badminton', 'Cricket'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Hockey'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the National Calendar of India?',
      choices: ['Hindu Calendar', 'Saka Calendar', 'Gregorian Calendar', 'None'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Saka Calendar'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Who was the first Vice President of India to receive Bharat Ratna Award?',
      choices: ['A. P. J. Abdul Kalam', 'Rajendra Prasad', 'Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan', 'Vallabhbhai Patel'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is NOT a soil type?',
      choices: ['Clay', 'Silt', 'Sand', 'Granite'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Granite'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which vitamins are water-soluble?',
      choices: ['Vitamin A', 'Vitamin B', 'Vitamin E', 'Vitamin K'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Vitamin B'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The uppermost layer of the atmosphere is:',
      choices: ['Mesosphere', 'Exosphere', 'Ionosphere', 'Stratosphere'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Exosphere'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Bannerghatta National Park is located in which state?',
      choices: ['Odisha', 'Sikkim', 'Karnataka', 'Tamil Nadu'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Karnataka'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Ranchi is the capital of which state?',
      choices: ['Jharkhand', 'Karnataka', 'Lakshadweep', 'Madhya Pradesh'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Jharkhand'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the capital of New Zealand?',
      choices: ['Berlin', 'Belgrade', 'Budapest', 'Wellington'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Wellington'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Who invented Heavy Hydrogen?',
      choices: ['Thomas Edison', 'L.C. Uray', 'J.L. Baird', 'Marie Curie'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['L.C. Uray'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which sport is associated with the Santosh Trophy?',
      choices: ['Cricket', 'Football', 'Badminton', 'Tennis'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Football'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the maximum strength of Rajya Sabha?',
      choices: ['250', '525', '285', '550'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['250'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The parliament of USA is called:',
      choices: ['Congress', 'Parliament', 'People\'s Assembly', 'Senate'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Congress'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which city is located on the banks of the Sutlej?',
      choices: ['Ludhiana', 'Sri Nagar', 'Kota', 'Hyderabad'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Ludhiana'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which is the largest atomic power plant in India?',
      choices: ['Tarapur', 'Kakrapar', 'Narora', 'Kudankulam'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Kudankulam'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Who was the author of Ramayana?',
      choices: ['Kalidas', 'Ved Vyas', 'Valmiki', 'Tulsi Das'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Valmiki'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which is the prime tributary of Ganga that meets at Allahabad?',
      choices: ['Brahmaputra', 'Yamuna', 'Krishna', 'Bhima'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Yamuna'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'FIFA headquarters is located in which country?',
      choices: ['France', 'Germany', 'Switzerland', 'Portugal'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Switzerland'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the unit of Force in the SI system?',
      choices: ['Watt', 'Joule', 'Newton', 'Pascal'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Newton'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which stadium is located in Ahmedabad?',
      choices: ['Narendra Modi Stadium', 'Eden Gardens', 'Rajiv Gandhi Stadium', 'Wankhede Stadium'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Narendra Modi Stadium'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Kempe Gowda International Airport is located in:',
      choices: ['Lucknow', 'Varanasi', 'Guwahati', 'Bengaluru'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Bengaluru'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'In which country was the first Commonwealth Games held?',
      choices: ['United Kingdom', 'Canada', 'Australia', 'New Zealand'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Canada'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which country\'s intelligence agency is known as RAW?',
      choices: ['Japan', 'China', 'Israel', 'India'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['India'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which is the longest National Highway in India?',
      choices: ['NH-1', 'NH-2', 'NH-7', 'NH-10'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['NH-7'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the minimum age to become Prime Minister?',
      choices: ['35', '30', '25', '21'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['25'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The McMahon Line demarcates Indian boundary with:',
      choices: ['Tibet', 'Nepal', 'Burma', 'Bangladesh'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Tibet'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'When is Teacher\'s Day celebrated in India?',
      choices: ['15 January', '8 October', '21 June', '5 September'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['5 September'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Who was the first Tirthankara in Jainism?',
      choices: ['Rishabhanatha', 'Parsavanath', 'Mahavira', 'Munisuvrata'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Rishabhanatha'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The Gayatri Mantra is from which Veda?',
      choices: ['Rig Veda', 'Chandogya Upanishad', 'Samaveda', 'Atharvaveda'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Rig Veda'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which period is NOT part of the Stone Age?',
      choices: ['Paleolithic Period', 'Chalcolithic Period', 'Mesolithic Period', 'Neolithic Period'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Chalcolithic Period'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Who is known as the father of Indian prehistory?',
      choices: ['Howard Carter', 'John Evans', 'Herodotus', 'Robert Bruce Foote'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Robert Bruce Foote'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The Great Bath of Indus Valley civilization is found at:',
      choices: ['Harappa', 'Mohenjo-Daro', 'Ropar', 'Kalibangan'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Mohenjo-Daro'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which was the only Indus site with an artificial brick dockyard?',
      choices: ['Lothal', 'Kalibangan', 'Harappa', 'Mohenjo-Daro'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Lothal'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'In the early Rigvedic period, what was considered the most valuable property?',
      choices: ['Land', 'Cow', 'Women', 'Water'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Cow'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'The primary source of Indian music and art comes from which Veda?',
      choices: ['Rig Veda', 'Samaveda', 'Yajurveda', 'Atharvaveda'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Samaveda'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Kaziranga National Park is located in which state?',
      choices: ['Uttarakhand', 'Himachal Pradesh', 'Uttar Pradesh', 'Assam'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Assam'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Find the next number in the series: 0, 2, 8, 14, ?, 34',
      choices: ['20', '23', '24', '25'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['24'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Complete the series: 28, 33, 31, 36, ?, 39',
      choices: ['32', '34', '38', '40'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['34'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Find the next term: 1, 5, 13, 25, 41, ?',
      choices: ['51', '57', '61', '63'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['61'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the primary purpose of an interrogative sentence?',
      choices: ['To make a statement', 'To convey excitement', 'To express a command', 'To ask a question'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['To ask a question'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which punctuation mark is used at the end of a declarative sentence?',
      choices: ['Exclamation mark (!)', 'Period (.)', 'Question mark (?)', 'Comma (,)'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Period (.)'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is an example of an imperative sentence?',
      choices: ['She is reading a book', 'The cat is sleeping', 'Bring me some water', 'They were playing football'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Bring me some water'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which interrogative word is used to inquire about a person\'s identity?',
      choices: ['Where', 'What', 'Who', 'When'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['Who'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which country is hosting the Kabaddi World Cup 2025?',
      choices: ['India', 'China', 'England', 'Japan'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['India'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Complete the number series: 10, 100, 200, 310, ?',
      choices: ['400', '410', '420', '430'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['430'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Find the missing number: 8, 9, 8, 7, 10, 9, 6, 11, 10, ?, 12',
      choices: ['5', '7', '8', '11'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['5'],
      score: 10,
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is an example of a declarative sentence?',
      choices: ['Would you like some tea?', 'Don\'t forget your umbrella', 'How are you feeling today?', 'The sun rises in the east'],
      type: 'MCQs',
      correctAnswers: ['The sun rises in the east'],
      score: 10,
    }
  ],
}